

3 Harrock Road Clayton-Le-Woods, Leyland, Lancashire PR25 5TX

Mobile: 0774 287 27 87

Email: nickelse@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I'm a Web and Graphics Designer who is a graduate from The University of Central Lancashire with over 9 years of in-house and studio experience.

I love being a designer and pursue it with great passion. I'm always looking to learn and develop my skills as well as working on projects that make me proud with great design principles at the heart of everything I do.

Bē /nickelse

/in/nickelse

in

EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGNER

Boohoo | Jan 2019 - Present

I am working as a UX Designer for Boohoo, who are one of the world's largest online fashion stores. I work on their Boohoo, Boohoo Man and Nasty Gal brands.

One main aspect of this role is identifying key areas where we can improve the user experience across the board from optimising the way a page functions to something as small as changing how different elements look and interact. Part of my role includes me creating split A/B tests to monitor and review any changes I make as well as use different analytic tools like Google Analytics, Content Blocks, Monetate and Hot Jar to guide my design choices and hypothesis'.

This role requires me to also be fully autonomous so that I can create wireframes in Adobe XD, then move on to high fidelity mock ups of my user experiences and finally being able to code and action any changes using HTML, CSS & jQuery. I am part of 4 person UX squad, so I also peer review every experience that the department produces so that we can be sure it is up to the high standards expected of a major online prescence.

I am also required to be very flexible and organised as due to the nature and high-speed of the business different projects can come up, so I have to take these onboard and organise my workflow appropriately, as well as attend regular meetings with other departments so that we can find any other areas we could potentially improve.

SENIOR WEB DESIGNER

EKM Systems | May 2015 - Jan 2019

I worked as a Senior Web Designer for EKM, who are one of the UK's largest e-commerce store provider for SME.

At EKM I have had two roles, I started off as a client facing Senior Designer working on their custom design jobs ranging from budgets of £1,000 to £5,000+, after doing that role for 3 months I moved over to their internal design department where my role is to lead projects from design to final concept based on building themes for shop merchants to use, this includes producing low and high fidelity proofs in Photoshop, Illustrator and Sketch to coding the HTML, CSS, and Javascript. I have had exposure to split A/B testing and the use of Hot Jar monitoring to gather user-data which helps to guide and improve user experiences on the projects I've worked on, admittedly this hasn't been as much of a day-to-day aspect of my role as I'd have liked but I am keen to explore more data driven design in the future as well as placing a heavier importance on usability research in general. I'm also the 'Product Owner' for the design team which includes organising daily scrums with the team, to making sure that the current projects we're working on are all going to plan and budget.

My role heavily involves me making sure that good design principles are followed with everything project that we do, making sure that good UX practices are at the heart of everything the department produces, this involves me making sure that I am always up to date with the latest design and usability trends and evaluating how any new technologies or information can be applied to the platform. This includes researching the industry our projects will target to find trends from features to colour schemes and beyond, we'll also use industry standard research from companies like Baymard to help guide the usability on our projects.

I am also mentoring a junior web designer as well as five web design apprentices, helping them develop their web design knowledge and skills further as well as having a hand in giving feedback and checking the quality of design work within the department.

SENIOR DESIGNER / DESIGN STUDIO SUPERVISOR

Freestart PLC | May 2009 - May 2015

As well as being a Senior Designer for the company I was also a supervisor for my department which involved me mentoring and supervising 2 junior web designers, making sure they met their deadlines, assigning them appropriate work and that everything was done to a high standard.

My day to day duties included dealing with all bespoke work, creating new templates for the business to sell and dealing with any maintenance or updates that were needed within the business. I was also responsible for any digital artwork that the company created from brochures and user guides to logos and re-branding projects bot externally and internally.

I started out at Freestart PLC as Junior Web Designer straight out of university and worked my way up to Senior / Supervisor level.

CUSTOMER SERVICE ADVISOR

Shop Direct Group | Sep 2002 - Jun 2009

I worked as a customer service advisor in a part-time capacity whilst studying at university.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) WEB & MULTIMEDIA DESIGN

UCLAN | Sep 2005 - May 2008

Obtained a 2:1 qualification at the University of Central Lancashire in Preston, Lancashire.

GNVQ & AVCE ICT

Runshaw College | Sep 2002 - May 2005

GNVQ Qualification & AVCE in Information Communication Technology. BTEC in E-Business

GCSE CERTIFICATES

Wellfield High School | Sep 1997 - May 2002

GCSE's in English, Math, Science, ICT, History, French and Design and Technology GCSE

SKILLS

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP	ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR
ADOBE XD	SKETCH
HTML	CSS
JQUERY	JAVASCRIPT
AGILE WORKING	AGILE PRODUCT OWNER

REFERENCES

LEON HAYES - SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

M: 07496 828 865

MARK GERRARD - CTO @ FREESTART PLC

M: 07521 505 185

PORTFOLIO

You can view my online portfolio which features all my latest projects on my Behance page @ https://www.behance.net/nickelse